FASHION STORE
Processed by 繁化姬 dict-cc3bb69e-r1048 @ 2024/07/07 00:29:06 | https://zhconvert.org
I'm done getting changed.
我换好衣服了
Same here.
我也换好了
Me too.
妾身也是
You can come out now.
那就出来吧
How do I look?
好看吗
Super cute!
超可爱的
Will this do?
这样就行了吗
I don't see how this is attractive.
妾身不懂好看在哪
You both look great in those outfits.
你们穿起来也很好看
Am I right, Satou?
对吧 佐藤
Not bad.
还不错
Cat ears and horns?
猫耳? 角?
Is there an event going on?
是有什么活动吗
Those things on your head are too conspicuous.
头上的东西果然特别麻烦啊
All we have to do is to avoid drawing attention.
总之别引人注目就行了吧
Check this out.
你们看这件
This style will suit you too.
这种风格也很适合
Each of us can wear a different colour.
我们四个可以穿不同颜色
-Hime is having a great time. -It's lovely!
-小姬 她看起来真开心 -好可爱
TALES OF WEDDING RINGS
《婚戒物语》
JOOSTARS
(Joostars)
All right, we should figure out
好了 我们现在得想想
how to proceed with this situation.
今后该怎么办
I get it,
话是这么说
but there's nothing left
但光之门出现的那个地方
where the portal of light opened.
现在什么都没有
It was difficult to pull that off.
虽然很难办到
But the ability to cast that spell
但他就是因为能操控 那种程度的魔法
is what made him the Great Sage.
才会被称为大贤者吧
We can either wait for our people to come for us
看是要赌另一边的人会来接我们
or find a way back.
还是寻找其他从这里回去的方法
Whichever the case, we have no clue how to proceed.
不管是哪种 目前都毫无头绪
We are completely helpless.
可以说是束手无策
It's too early to give up.
怎么可以就这样投降
Aren't you worried about your country?
难道你不担心自己的国家吗
May I take your order?
您要点什么
The merchant guild will decide Needakitta's destination.
尼妲齐达是由商人公会决定去向
There's no need for me to worry.
所以我不担心自己的国家
My brother and the elder will keep Lomka safe.
洛姆加有皇兄和长老大人守护
I'd spent ten years in this world.
我基本上有十年都住在这个世界
What an optimistic bunch.
你们看得真开呢
That doesn't mean I've given up.
我也还没有放弃
But given our circumstances,
但事情变这样
we must prepare for the worst.
我们必须做好最坏的打算
By the way,
话说回来
all the worries don't seem to
你说了那么多
affect your appetite.
还是很能吃嘛
The desserts are simply too good.
因为这里的甜点很好吃
Sweet food is my favourite.
妾身最喜欢吃甜点了
I hope I have enough money to pay for this.
不知道钱够不够
Don't worry, let me take care of it.
别担心 由我来付吧
But I am anxious.
不过妾身很焦急
Despite knowing there's nothing we can do,
尽管知道束手无策
I still want to find a way back.
妾身还是想寻找回去的方法
But where do we even begin?
但是要怎么做呢
A place with a high density of mana
只要找到魔素丰富的地方
should be able to form a connection with our world.
应该就能连到那边
The first step is to find that place.
我们要先找出那个地方
We mustered the spirit
明明鼓起了干劲
but couldn't find any lead.
却没有找到任何线索
I'm actually surprised.
不过真意外
There are only humans on this land
这片土地只有人类
and no other races.
没有别的种族呢
All right! I'm going to increase the catfolk population!
好吧 我要先增加这里的猫人
I'm going to make babies with him!
和他生孩子
Stop!
别这样
I'll find a way to leave this extremely extraordinary land.
我会努力找出 离开这个终极异地的办法
Try your best, Princess Saphir.
所以瑟菲珞殿下也继续努力吧
By the way, Krystal,
对了 克莉丝朵
how are things going?
你回到这里之后
Weren't you going to further develop your relationship with the Ring King?
就要和戒王发展关系的事怎么样了
Well, that's up to Satou.
这件事取决于佐藤的决定
You have a promise, right?
你们约好了吧
Huh!?
吃惊
Well then, good night.
那晚安了
Good night.
晚安
The room is too cramped for all four of us.
四个人一起住果然太狭窄了
I'll be spending the night here.
我住这里
Are you sure we can let them be on their own?
让她们三个自己住没问题吗
They are staying next door. Nothing to worry about.
反正就在隔壁 没问题的
So...
我问你
Yes?
什么事
The bills for the clothes and food...
今天买衣服和吃饭的钱…
Oh...
那个啊
Gramps left a letter in my room.
爷爷在我的房间里留了一封信
If you are reading this letter,
你看到这封信
it means things didn't go as planned.
就代表事情发展不顺利
Sorry I can't be with you right now.
很抱歉不能陪在你身边
But all that matters is that you're safe.
不过只要你没事就好
There's nothing to worry about.
什么都不用担心
The house and the money are still here.
房子和钱都还留着
I made the arrangements so you could live here when necessary.
我已经事先做好准备 让你可以在这里生活
Please, forget about Arnulus.
希望你忘了亚努鲁斯
Live on and have a normal life.
作为一个平凡人过活
Gramps predicted
爷爷他…
things could end badly.
已经想到事情可能会变成这样
He told me not to be worried.
所以要我什么都别担心
I thought you went abroad.
你不是搬到国外去了吗
Well, something came up.
这个嘛 因为发生了一点问题
How did you spend your summer break?
你暑假都在做什么啊
Nothing special. Some family matters.
没什么啦 家里有点事
I thought I didn't have to come to school again.
我还以为自己不用再来学校了
A few days have passed.
就这样过了几天
Nephrites goes to the library every day
涅芙丽缇丝为了了解这个世界
to learn more about our world.
每天都去图书馆
Granart made some new friends in the neighbourhood.
葛兰纳托好像在附近交到了朋友
Saphir is always deep in thought.
瑟菲珞则是一直在沉思
Satou.
佐藤
You've been coming here every night.
你每晚都偷偷跑来看吧
I don't mind living here,
我是不介意
but I don't know if the princesses will say the same.
但公主们愿意待在这里吗
Don't you remember Gramps' last words?
你还记得爷爷最后说的话吗
He wanted you to free the princesses from their fate with the rings.
请你让公主们摆脱戒指的宿命
Everyone should find their happiness in this world.
大家必须各自在这个世界找到幸福
You too, Satou.
佐藤你也是
Leave the other world behind.
忘了另一个世界
Let's live happily
和我在这个世界
in this world.
幸福地生活吧
Okay?
好吗
To live happily...
幸福地…
Satou?
佐藤
Hime.
小姬
What is that?
怎么了
The shrine!
神龛…
A girl came out of the shrine!
从神龛里冒出一个女孩子
It's been too long.
这么长的时间
I've been waiting for you.
我一直在等你
We finally meet.
终于见到你了
Ring King.
戒王
Sorry for interrupting.
不好意思打扰你们
I'm going back in.
我回去了
Wait! You called me the Ring King.
等一下 你刚刚叫我"戒王"
Are you actually...
你该不会是…
The guardian of the Ring of Earth,
我是守护土之戒的人
Amber Idanokan.
安芭卢·伊达诺坎
A Ring Princess has been living in our world this whole time?
戒指公主原来在这个世界吗
Long ago, after the great battle against the Abyss King ended,
很久以前 与深渊王的一战结束后
a small number of dwarves survived.
只有少数的矮人活了下来
The race of dwarfs would face extinction one day,
总有一天矮人族会绝后
and Idanokan, the Kingdom of Earth, would fall.
土之国伊达诺坎会灭亡
To prepare for their extinction and ensure the ring would be passed down,
为了迎接灭亡 守护戒指的传承
the dwarves created an immortal vessel for the ring.
矮人创造了能永远存活的戒指容器
The name was Amber.
安芭卢
Created?
创造…
I was a creation.
我是被创造出来的东西
A substitute for the dwarven princess.
是矮人公主的替身
I was sent to this world along with the ring.
我和戒指一起被送来这个世界
It was an effort to ensure the ring would not be lost
为了不让任何人抢走戒指
and was safely delivered to the Ring King.
并送到戒王的手上
I've been waiting for centuries.
我一直等了好几百年
And finally,
然后
you are here.
戒王你来了
Now, become one with me.
来吧 和我结合
Defeat the Abyss King
打倒深渊王
and bring peace to Arnulus.
带给亚努鲁斯和平吧
No!
不行
Arnulus is lost.
亚努鲁斯已经没救了
The Abyss King came back to life.
深渊王复活了
It was the reason we fled to this world.
我们才会逃来这里
We lost. Therefore,
我们已经输了 所以…
Satou must never go back to that world!
佐藤绝对不能回去
Hime...
小姬…
Is that so?
是吗
In other words,
也就是说
I can't fulfil Amber's duty.
我无法达成安芭卢的使命
Come to me when you change your mind.
要是你改变心意就告诉我
I'm used to waiting for the man who never came.
我已经习惯等迟迟不来的人了
Hey, Satou.
喂 佐藤
Can you come home early tomorrow?
明天你能早点回来吗
Every day here is so boring.
我每天都无聊得要命
I didn't do my summer homework.
我完全没写暑假作业
I'll have to attend extra classes for some time.
所以这阵子都要去学校补课
You are our husband.
你是我们的丈夫
You should spend more time
如果不多陪陪我们
with us.
我会伤脑筋的
Yes.
好
Nephrites seems bored as well.
涅芙丽缇丝也很无聊的样子
What about the library?
图书馆呢
Well...
因为那个…
Since I've been going there every day, the people remember my face.
我每天都去 结果长相被记住了
Now I find it a bit daunting to go there.
害我变得不太想去
Saphir has been cooped up at home.
瑟菲珞也一直窝在家里
Aren't you bored?
不觉得无聊吗
I'm doing all right.
妾身觉得还好
By the way, Ring King,
对了 戒王
you and Krystal were out until late night yesterday.
你昨天和克莉丝朵出去到很晚
What were you doing?
到底是去做什么了
Actually, there was...
这个嘛 其实…
We went to the convenience store.
我们只是去便利商店而已
Isn't that right, Satou?
对吧 佐藤
Yeah...
对
Hime,
小姬
shouldn't we tell them about Amber?
不告诉她们安芭卢的事好吗
Can we even make a difference by going back?
回去了又能怎么办
Can we really defeat the Abyss King
只要收集到所有戒指
by collecting all the rings?
真的就能打倒深渊王吗
Are you sure you can defeat a monstrosity like that?
你真的有办法打倒那种怪物吗
We must stay in this world and find happiness.
我们必须在这个世界得到幸福
We should've left the house sooner.
我们太晚出门了
Yeah.
对啊
Let's run.
快跑吧
Amber! What are you doing there?
安芭卢 你在做什么
Doing what I'm meant to do.
我只是在做自己该做的事
It's my duty to watch over the Ring King.
看着戒王就是我的使命
It's my destiny to be found by the Ring King.
然后被戒王找到就是我的宿命
When I heard your voice last night,
昨天我听到你来找我的声音
I thought you finally came looking for me.
我心想你终于来了
However, it wasn't me that you sought.
但是戒王在找的不是我
You were searching for the happiness
戒王在找的
the Ring Princess of Light mentioned.
是光戒公主所说的幸福
Welcome!
欢迎光临 欢迎光临
High quality at a low price!
很便宜哦
There are carrots.
有胡萝卜呢
Apple.
苹果
Amber?
安芭卢…
Their apples are delicious.
这里的苹果很好吃
The people running this shop
这家店的人
are a family that has safeguarded the shrine for generations.
是代代守护山上神社的一族
Their offerings are always the delicious apples.
供品一直都是很好吃的苹果
I never knew.
我完全不知道
"DELICIOUS APPLES! 178 YEN EACH!" Apples...
(美味苹果 一颗178圆) 苹果吗…
Where did she go?
人呢
I can help you return to Arnulus.
我能让戒王回到亚努鲁斯
I was gifted with that power.
我被赋予了这种力量
Form the pact of ring with me
只要和我缔结戒指的契约
so I can regain my power
我就能取回力量
to open a portal to Arnulus.
打开通往亚努鲁斯的门
It's finally over.
总算结束了
Where is the Ring Princess of Light?
光戒公主呢
She finished her homework and went home.
她先写完功课回家了
She has people waiting for her at home.
因为她家有其他人
You are very eager to go back to Arnulus.
你本来恨不得马上回亚努鲁斯吗
That was the plan,
我本来是这么想的
but when I saw the looks on Hime's face...
但是一看到小姬的脸就…
She has a point.
她说得对
We probably won't make a difference
就算现在收集到所有戒指
by collecting all the rings.
也可能什么都做不了了
Don't worry.
别担心
The rings' power is absolute.
戒指的力量是绝对的
They can certainly seal the Abyss King away.
一定能封印深渊王
The dwarves told me so.
矮人是这么告诉我的
Just like the legend?
就像传说那样吗
I won't force you.
我不会强迫你
I was created for the Ring King.
戒王就是我被创造出来的意义
You must witness my existence until the very end.
所以我必须看着戒王直到死去
Until the very end...
直到死去…
I want to know the meaning of my creation.
我想知道自己被创造出来的意义
I want to measure the value of the time I spent waiting for you.
想衡量一直等待的时间有何价值
That sounds heavy to me.
好沉重啊
I am not heavy at all.
我一点也不沉重
I weigh as much as a normal person.
我的重量就和一般人一样
Just kidding.
刚刚那是玩笑
All the Ring Princesses
所有戒指公主都一样
live for the Ring King
为了戒王而活
and devote themselves to saving the world.
为了世界鞠躬尽瘁
Such is the meaning of our births.
这就是我们诞生的意义
Our duty is a difficult one.
这个使命一点也不轻松
The meaning of life...
活着的意义…
She's right.
说得也是
Can you hand me the ring?
能把戒指给我吗
Did you change your mind?
你改变心意了吗
No. I found the answer.
不 我找到答案了
I must do what I'm meant to do.
我要做我该做的事
I see.
是吗
I'm so happy to hear that.
我好高兴
Don't you want to know why?
你不问我理由吗
The will of the Ring King is mine as well.
戒王的意志就是我的意志
There's no need for a reason.
不需要理由
I see.
是吗
Hime...
小姬…
Sorry for startling you.
对不起 害你吓一跳
I thought about Gramps again.
我又想起爷爷了
But it's all right now.
不过已经没事了
I couldn't hold my tears just now.
我刚刚只是不自觉流泪
I'll get used to it very soon.
一定很快就会习惯了
That ring...
那个戒指…
The Ring of Earth.
是土之戒
We have all five rings now.
这样就收集到五只戒指了
Did you get that from Amber?
你从安芭卢那里收下的吗
Why?
为什么
I want to go back to Arnulus.
我要回到亚努鲁斯
No! You can't!
不行 你不能回去
We are only here
我们现在会在这里
because we didn't have all the rings.
是因为没有收集到五只戒指
But we have all of them now.
如果戒指都到齐了
It's time to go.
我们就得走
Of course I know!
我当然知道
But we are finally together again.
但我们好不容易又能在一起
What if you die in that world full of danger?
要是你死在那种危险的世界…
Is the duty of a Ring Princess
对你来说
so insignificant to you?
戒指的使命这么不重要吗
We grew up together in the past ten years.
你是我十年来的青梅竹马
That's all I know.
这就是我所知道的一切
Isn't that duty worth realising
这个使命
even if you have to give up
不是重要到即使抛弃这十年
those ten years?
你也必须达成吗
To break free from the fate of a Ring Princess,
如果想摆脱戒指的宿命
you must not run away or forget.
就不能逃避 也不能遗忘
The right way is to put an end to all of this.
而是真正结束这一切
Hime, let's face it together.
我们一起面对吧 小姬
I'll be right next to you this time.
这次我也会陪在你身边
You don't have to carry this duty by yourself any more.
这已经不是你一个人的使命了
As Gramps said,
爷爷说过
our bond powers the rings.
情意就是戒指的力量
No one in this world loves you more than I do.
我比任何世界的任何人都爱你
Don't worry, I can win the fight.
别担心 我不会输的
What? You sound so silly.
你在说什么啊 真蠢
But I'm relieved.
不过我放心了
There's no way you can lose with that spirit.
这样的你是不可能会输的
Hime...
小姬…
Well then, I should answer your love.
那么 我也必须回应你的爱
Satou.
佐藤
Why don't we fulfil our promise from that day?
现在就来实现当时的约定吧
You mean...
你是说…
Don't make me say it out loud.
别让我明讲啦
This feels like a dream.
好像在做梦
We're actually doing it in this room.
和佐藤你在这个房间做这种事
Hime...
小姬…
I'm getting a head start.
总觉得有点像偷跑
I feel sorry for the others.
有点对不起其他人
Didn't I tell you? My heart belongs to you alone.
我不是说过我的心里只有你吗
The teleportation device is ready.
转移魔法装置已经准备完成
We can now return to Arnulus...
这样就能回到亚努鲁斯…
Is this a bad time?
时机不对吗
The teleportation device can only be used once.
我的转移魔法装置只能用一次
What's the plan now?
你们打算怎么办
We are going back now! Immediately!
我们要回去 马上就用
Right, Hime?
小姬 可以吧
Yeah.
嗯
Satou, what happened?
佐藤 怎么了
No, don't get the wrong idea.
不是…对 是你想得那样没错
So, the time has come.
看来时机成熟了啊
You noticed?
你发现了吗
I'd be disappointed if you underestimated a catfolk's
要是小看猫人的洞察力
perceptiveness.
我会伤脑筋的
Granart, I want to apologise.
葛兰纳托 那个…对不起
No, I understand how you feel.
不 我能理解你的想法
There's no telling how bad the situation is in Arnulus.
我们的世界 现在根本不知道变怎样了
I was going to respect Satou's decision,
所以我本来想尊重佐藤的意思
but I also anticipated this outcome.
不过我也期待过会是这种结果
Hold on.
等一下
I'm completely at a loss here.
妾身完全搞不清楚状况
There's no time to explain. Anyway...
现在没时间详细解释 总之…
What?
什么
The girl is Amber Idanokan?
她是安芭卢·伊达诺坎
The Ring Princess of Earth?
土戒公主
Are we going back?
我们回得去了吗
Correct.
没错
We can head back to Arnulus now.
我们能回到亚努鲁斯了
I see.
是吗
I see. We can finally go back.
这样啊 能回去了啊
All right, we are all set.
好 准备好了
Let's go.
我们走吧
Huh? Are we going somewhere?
咦 我们要去哪里
Stay still and hold on tight.
你乖乖别动哦